Contact

Lagos, Nigeria

+234 805 363 7018 (Mobile)

jimohax@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesohakwe/ (LinkedIn)

https://github.com/Jimohax (GitHub)

https://jimohax.github.io/portfolio/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Bootstrap CSS

Javascript

Redux

React

Education

Ekiti state university

Ekiti State, Nigeria

B.Ed | Jun 2011 - May 2015

Educational Management (Computer Science)

 Gained a solid foundation in Computer science and the software development cycle.

James Ohakwe

Full Stack Software Engineer

MongoDB | Express | React | Node

Lagos, Nigeria

Summary

I am a results-driven Full Stack Software Engineer, specializing in M.E.R.N. (MongoDB, ExpressJs, ReactJs, NodeJs) with experience working on wordpress, UI/UX, frontend and backend platforms.

My interest in programming is motivated by curiosity and the possibility of finding simple and unique solutions to complex problems using tech. With a background in computer science gotten from my bachelor's degree, more than two years full stack experience, strong communication and leadership skills, I can handle tasks unsupervised, collaborate effectively in a team, set goals and lead a team to achieve those goals.

My hobbies include playing basketball and the guitar. I also love watching sci-fi-movies and reading books; I am currently reading Goals by Bryan Tracy.

Work Experience

Workmate Team | Aug 2022 - present

Software Developer (Full-stack)

- -Managing cutting-edge technologies to improve applications.
- -Developing functional and sustainable web applications with clean
- -Leveraging Node and React JS to build management systems.
- -Writing scalable and secure restful APIs for frontend consumption.

Orglearning Consult | Jan 2019 - Jul 2022

Tech Specialist

- Lead a team to Develop and maintain educational websites with portal services, database management and payment systems.
- integrated chat and video conferencing applications
- Collaborated with educators and lead the switch from traditional to virtual teaching/learning during the COVID19 pandemic.

Rescripting consult | Jul 2016 - Nov 2018

Tech Consultant

- -Delivering wordpress projects as well as gaining proficiency in the latest web technologies:
- Provided tech support for educators.